Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Motion Pictures
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, motion pictures
1930-2003
RU 839
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.75
The materials consist of 16mm motion picture films and videotapes of athletic events at Yale.
Yale University
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-C (YRG 38-C), Audiovisual materials and memorabilia documenting athletics at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original motion picture films and videotapes may not be played. Researchers should consult with a reference archivist for policies and procedures governing the creation of use copies.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of 16mm motion picture films and videotapes of athletic events at Yale.
- Athletic videotapes, Circa 1930-1980s; Accession 2006-A-232
  - NCAA Honors Dinner
    - 1991 Feb 14 [commercially-produced], videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
      - Tone Grant segment [2:26] [commercially-produced], videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
    - 1993 (Don Schollander) [commercially-produced], videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
    - 1994 (Calvin Hill) [50:00] [commercially-produced], videotape (VHS) (Box 4)
    - 1995 Jan 8, San Diego, CA [1:27:55]; commercially-produced videotape (VHS) (Box 5)
    - 1996 Jan 7, Dallas, TX; commercially-produced videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
    - 1998 (Lawrie Mifflin) [77:20] [commercially-produced], videotape (VHS) (Box 7)
    - 2000 NCAA Honors Dinner program featuring Lisa Rosenblum, Tennis, 2000 January 9; videotape (VHS) (Box 24)
    - 2001 (Jack Ford) [1:44:00] [commercially-produced], videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
    - 2004 (Ginny Gilder) [commercially-produced], videotape (VHS) (Box 9)
  - Various
    - AYA "Athletics at Yale Panel Discussion", 1995 October 26-28; videotape (VHS) (Box 23)
    - Yale Football '35, '36, '37 seasons; featuring Gim Gillies ('38) interview with coach Ducky Pond, Clint Frank, Larry Kelly, undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 10)
    - Greater Buffalo Sports Hall of Fame induction of Bob Kiphuth [commercially-produced], 1997 September 10; videotape (VHS) (Box 11)
    - Varsity dinner (Amanda Walton), 2002 April 29; videotape (VHS) (Box 12)
    - Kiphuth panel discussion, 2003 May 30; videotape (VHS) (Box 13)
    - ECAC Honors Dinner (Amanda Walton), 2003; videotape (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Blue Leadership Ball, 2003 November 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 15)
    - Amanda Walton receiving award, Undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 16)
    - Breakfast to honor Chris Hetherington, Undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 17)
    - Yale athletics meeting, Undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 18)
    - Yale athletic honors ceremony, 1996; videotape (VHS) (Box 19)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 19U)
  - Women's athletics
    - Yale University Women's athletics [15:00], Undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 20)
      - Use copy, Undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 20U)
    - A. Bartlett Giamatti, "Celebration of women's athletics at Yale," Yale Commons; audiocassette, 1986 April 9 (Box 21)
    - "Pioneers and Competitors: A Tribute to Women's Athletics at Yale", 1999 April; videotape (VHS) (Box 22)
- Croquet and tennis videotapes, 1983, 1991; Accession 2006-A-235
  - Croquet vs. Harvard, 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Arthur Ashe, Kiphuth Fellow Speech, 1983 February 10; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
- Athletic films, Circa 1970s; Accession 2008-A-056
  - Athletics at Yale, Undated; film reel (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Indoor exercise, 1975; film reel (16mm) (Box 2)